Cassia Almeida, CSM, CSD

Lead Developer at Blue Insurance

Personal Email: <u>almeidacassia@outlook.com</u>

Personal Website: https://cassialmeida.github.io/

Github Page: https://github.com/cassialmeida

Mobile: +353 83 8826240

<u>About</u>

Lead Developer with broad experience in software development, with consistent background in people and project management of distributed teams.

Certified Scrum Master (CSM), Scrum Developer (CSD), actively working on Agile Methodologies and good practices adoption.

Certifications

- Certified Scrum Master
- Certified Scrum Developer
- Product Owner Open

<u>Skills</u>

- Databases SQL Server, Oracle
- Skills and Knowledge: C#, ASP.NET Forms, Windows Forms, ASP.NET MVC, Silverlight 3.0, WPF, WCF, ASP.NET Web API, Microsoft Office Sharepoint Services, Microsoft Office Project, SQL Server Jobs (SSIS), Reporting Services, Entity Framework, LINQ, Javascript, JQuery, JQuery Mobile, HTML, CSS, KnockoutJS, AngularJS, API Google and Google Maps.

Work Experience

Blue Insurance

Lead Developer

January 2017 - Till date

Key technologies: NET/C#, Entity Framework, .NET Core, WCF, Web API, ASP.NET MVC, Angular, ADO.NET, ASP. NET Web Forms, Microsoft Reporting Services, Unit Testing

- Lead Developer of the Greenfield Team.
- Working with Managers to contribute to high level project schedules, resource plans for the project, and project costs.
- Often function as the primary technology contact, communicating frequently about schedules, deliverables, and risk.
- Assist in identifying project requirements, strategies and schedules in support of project/initiatives analysis and prioritization.
- Participate in hiring process, team assignments, and cross-training.

Dell

May 2014 - October 2016

Software Developer Senior Analyst

Key technologies: NET/C#, Entity Framework, WCF, ASP.NET Forms, ASP.NET Web Forms, SSIS, SSRS, ADO.NET, Javascript, SQL Server, Oracle, TFS

- Lead Developer of distributed team members in United States, Canada, Romania, Brazil and India for Dell Financial Service projects.
- Senior developer of 7 applications under Dell Financial Services segment, providing technical direction, design principles and standards to guide other developers.
- Actively working in all software project phases, from conception to post-installation warranty.
- Continuous integration environment using TFS for versioning and tasks control.
- Responsible for working together with the business partner to understand requirements and processes.
- Award received in Q2 2015 as a result of the work performed during a high level production incident.

Softforce

October 2011 - May 2014

Software Developer

Key technologies: ASP.NET Forms, ASP.NET MVC 3 and 4, WPF, WCF, Silverlight, JQuery Mobile, KnockoutJS, Google Maps API, SQL Server, Windows Phone Development

- Responsible for design, code and create documentation as needed.
- Application development for web, desktop and mobile devices using the ASP.NET Forms, ASP.NET MVC 3 and 4 (Razor), WPF, WCF, Silverlight, JQuery Mobile, KnockoutJS and SQL Server database.

Hewlett Packard - HP

December 2009 - October 2011

Software Developer

Key technologies: Java (Spring MVC), WPF, WCF, Silverlight with Framework 4.0, SQL Server and Oracle databases

- Responsible for design, code and create documentation as needed.
- Worked together with development team on troubleshooting bugs or issues reported by customers.

Education

- 2016 Full Stack Web Development Certification Free Code Camp
- 2015 Certified Scrum Master Course Adaptworks
- 2015 Creative Projects Management: Methodologies and Processes University: Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio Grande do Sul
- 2015 Graduate Course IT Project Management
 University: Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio Grande do Sul
- 2014 Certified Scrum Developer Course Adaptworks
- 2013 Agile Project Management with Scrum PMTech
- 2008 2012 Computer Science Bachelor's degree
 University: Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio Grande do Sul